26. Hikikomori. There may be more than a million of them, but you'd never know it. They're hidden away,
locked inside houses or rooms. They're Hikikomori, the invisible people of Japan. Hikikomori, in
Japanese with drawing or being confined, are people, mostly men, who go to great lengths to
pull out of society. In the West, this would be called extreme social phobia or agoraphobia,
fear of being outside. But the Hikikomori situation is more widespread in Japan. It is also mostly
ignored, out of shame. One boy walked into his family's kitchen when he was 14, shut the door,
and refused to come out. The family eventually built another kitchen to use. Takeshi, 19,
spent four years in his bedroom, listening to music and playing video games. YS actually
stayed in his room for over 13 years. He was tired of being bullied at school and couldn't
take being out in the world anymore. Bullying, breakups, or tests are often triggers that cause
these young men to snap and become Hikikomori. Dr. Henry Grubb, who has studied Hikikomori,
says the Japanese way of avoiding confrontation makes it worse. In the West, Hikikomori would be
treated as being mentally ill, whereas in Japan, they're seen as a family problem. It's also common
for Japanese mothers to serve their sons. Instead of making their boys do something difficult, like
go outside, Japanese mothers may simply attend to their boys' needs. Then, when schools don't
pursue children who don't attend, it becomes very easy for a society to pretend the Hikikomori
don't exist. But Hikikomori cannot be served for the rest of their lives by aging parents. Groups
like Newstart are trying to get these boys out and teach them how to fend for themselves before
it's too late.